JUSTIN COLLINS

728 Barkley Circle Alabaster, AL 35007 205.281.6775 jbc0981@gmail.com www.justincollinstech.com

Qualified IT Professional with over 10 years of experience in various technologies including Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, and Infrastructure Automation. Looking for a challenging DevOps role with a cloud-oriented software team using current technologies and methodologies where I can grow as an engineer, while helping the organization achieve efficient, repeatable application deployments.

ABILITIES

- Scripting using PowerShell, Ruby, and Bash
- Agile Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery processes with Jenkins CI
- Infrastructure as code with PowerShell DSC and Chef
- Application deployments to data centers as well as the cloud (Azure/AWS)
- Source control management in Git, Mercurial, and VSTS Git
- Containerization with Docker

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jenkon, Birmingham, AL

DevOps Engineer / SCM Manager, July 2017 to present

- Administer and support Jenkon infrastructure both on premises and in the cloud
- Manage source code repository in Mercurial and Git
- · Migrated source code repository from on premises hosted Mercurial to cloud based Git
- Migrated all builds from legacy CCNet to Jenkins
- Created automated deployment jobs using Jenkins
- Migrated on premises customer environments to Azure
- Created DevOps pipeline for build automation and deployment
- Trained development teams on Jenkins and CI/CD practices
- Mentored other engineers on DevOps philosophies and culture
- Administer Jenkon build environment
- Used Docker to move Jenkins build environment to containers

Casamba Incorporated, Birmingham, AL

Production Services App Specialist / DBA, October 2016 to July 2017

- In October of 2016, Casamba purchased the TherapySource division of SourceMed.
- Accomplishments since acquisition:
- Lead a team of 6 people during the Data Center migration from the SourceMed data center to the new Casamba data center
- Worked with development to help automate the TherapySource application upgrade process.
- Collaborate with Casamba IT to troubleshoot and correct Citrix installations and configurations.

SourceMed, Birmingham, AL

Production Services App Specialist / DBA, July 2015 – October 2016

- Create, maintain, and deploy application installation packages for SourceMed hosted and customer hosted environments.
- Monitor and maintain database daily and weekly maintenance on over 100 servers with multiple databases per server.
- Collaborate with server support regarding server configuration and management, including operating system installation, storage space, and server prerequisites needed by the TherapySource application.
- Develop automation scripts for application deployments as well as tasks requested by developers, customer support representatives and implementation managers.
- Create scripts and automation tasks to process external data into our databases from 3rd party interface tools as well as flat file data.
- Assist lower support tiers with database and production related issues.
- Train lower support tiers in SQL processes and SQL scripting.
- Troubleshoot SQL and data import errors in the SourceMed Analytics application.
- Deploy SQL and web site fixes to production for the SourceMed Analytics application.
- Work with implementation managers on performing application and database migrations from customer hosted environments to SourceMed hosted environments.

Regions Financial Corporation, Birmingham, AL

Database Reporting Analyst II / DBA, June 2014 to July 2015

- Develop and maintain SSIS packages for loading data from third party systems to be used by internal web applications.
- Debug and Code Review database code for web developers to improve performance and scalability.
- Develop and maintain SQL database objects for use web applications as well as SQL jobs.
- Collaborate with web developers regarding process standards and best practices.
- Coordinate with Regions Technology for changes and enhancements to the test and development databases such as backups and scheduling.

Daxko, Homewood, AL

Software & Systems Configuration Engineer, April 2013 – June 2014

- Collaborated with the rest of the Systems and IT team and developers for installing and configuring a new data center consisting of 6 web servers, 8 clustered database servers, 4 application servers, as well new build and utility servers.
- Worked with other infrastructure engineers to develop automated processes for allocating resources in our Amazon Web Services environment using Chef and Cloud Formation.
- Developed scripts to automate server configuration changes as well as to install these services through Chef scripts during server automation.
- Administered production and QA web servers including IIS and Apache Tomcat.
- Built, packaged, and deployed website and database code to production servers.
- Configured and administered the JIRA server used for development, enhancement, and bug tracking system hosted internally on CentOS with a MySQL database.

- Co-chaired the Change Control Board to ensure proper review and documentation of releases and production changes were performed in adherence with compliancy standards.
- Worked with developers to improve the continuous integration systems using Rake and PowerShell scripts with Jenkins CI.
- Administered production and QA build servers using Jenkins CI.
- Administered Daxko's source code library using Git at GitHub as well as BitBucket.

Daxko, Homewood, AL

Production Support Engineer, July 2011 – April 2013

- Communicate with Customer Support regarding outstanding cases for customers.
- Monitor application performance using New Relic and PowerShell scripts reporting IIS statistics.
- Complete Tier 2 support cases for customers based on severity and priority using various technologies including but not limited to Microsoft SQL Server and Microsoft Visual Studio.
- Communicate with the QA team on fixes to be deployed to the production environments. Analyze error logs and research data and code fixes for the development team to correct.
- Work with the Change Control Board regarding fixes that need to be deployed outside of planned releases.

Amplicare, Birmingham, AL

Software Engineer, January 2010 – March 2011

- Development of external web applications for our clients as well as internal windows applications and services.
- Develop and maintain SQL queries as well as stored procedures used in the development of our applications.
- Deploy new functionality to our QA environment for testing.
- QA new functionality before production deployments.
- Provide estimates for enhancement requests from clients.

EBSCO Industries, Birmingham, AL

.NET Developer, February 2008 – January 2010

- Create and maintain new web functionality and web sites for Scientific, Technical, and Medical journal publishers around the world.
- Perform maintenance and bug fixes on current web sites.
- Merge production code with development and testing environments.
- Communicate with Quality Assurance regarding testing and build schedules.
- Communicate with Architects regarding enhancements and code corrections.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Azure
- Jenkins CI
- · Microsoft Windows Server
- Linux
- OS X
- .NET

- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft PowerShell
- Gi
- Ruby/Rake
- JIRA
- Docker

EDUCATION

ITT Technical Institute, Bessemer, AL

Graduated with Honors - September 2007